handinhand2017.com 2019-12-25

# Privacy Policy & Legal Disclosures | Comic Relief USA

### Privacy Policy

Effective Date: November 12, 2018

_**1\. Introduction and Overview.**_

This Privacy Policy describes how Comic Relief, Inc. (AGB), a nonprofit Delaware corporation, and its various programs (“ **Comic Relief** ,” “ **we** ,” “ **our** ,” or “ **us** ”) collects, uses, and shares information about you and applies to your use of any online service location that posts a link to this Privacy Policy and all features, content, and other services that we own, control and make available through such online service location (collectively, the “Service”). This Privacy Policy does not apply to our information collection activities outside of the Service (unless otherwise stated below or at the time of collection). By using the Service, you agree to our Terms of Use and to our collection, use and disclosure practices, and other activities as described in this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree and consent, discontinue use of the Service.

_**2\. Information Collection.**_

**A. Information You Provide.**

We and our Service Providers (defined below) may collect information you provide directly via the Service. For example, we collect information when you make a donation, access our content, or otherwise communicate or transact with us through the Service.

The information we collect may include Personal Information.  **“Personal Information”  **is information that identifies you personally (whether alone or in combination), such as your first and last name, e-mail address, phone number, postal address, and payment card and shipping information. You may choose to voluntarily submit certain other information to us through the Service, including Personal Information, but you are solely responsible for your own Personal Information in instances where we have not requested that you submit such information to us.

Personal Information once  **“de-identified”**  is not subject to this Privacy Policy and we and our Service Providers may treat it as non-Personal Information and use it without obligation to you except as prohibited by applicable law.

**B. Information Collected Automatically.**

We and our Service Providers may automatically collect certain information about you when you access or use the Service ( **“Usage Information”** ). Usage Information may include IP address, device identifier, browser type, operating system, data regarding network connected hardware, and information about your use of the Service. To the extent that we combine Usage Information with your Personal Information, we will treat the combined information as Personal Information under this Privacy Policy.

The methods that may be used on the Service to collect Usage Information include:

●  **Log Information:**

Log information is data about your use of the Service, such as IP address, browser type, internet service provider, referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamps, and related data, which is stored in log files.

● **  Information Collected by Tracking Technologies:**

Cookies, web beacons (also known as “tracking pixels”), embedded scripts, location-identifying technologies, voice processing technologies, device fingerprinting, in-app tracking methods, and other tracking technologies now and hereafter developed ( **“Tracking Technologies”** ) may be used to collect information about your interactions with the Service or e-mails, including information about your browsing and activity behavior.

**o Cookies**

A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a user’s device, which may be a session ID cookie or tracking cookie. Session cookies make it easier for you to navigate the Service and expire when you close your browser. Tracking cookies help in understanding how you use the Service, and remain longer. The Service may associate some or all of these types of cookies with your devices. Cookies may remain on your device for extended periods of time.

**o Web Beacons (“Tracking Pixels”)**

Web beacons are small graphic images, also known as “internet tags” or “clear gifs,” embedded in web pages and e-mail messages. Web beacons may be used to count the number of visitors to the Service, to monitor how users navigate the Service, and to count content views.

**o Embedded Scripts**

An embedded script is programming code designed to collect information about your interactions with the Service. It is temporarily downloaded onto your device from our web server or a third party with whom we work, is active only while you are connected to the Service, and deleted or deactivated thereafter.

Some information about your use of the Service and certain Third Party Services (defined below) may be collected using Tracking Technologies across time and services and used by us and third parties for purposes such as to associate different devices you use, and deliver relevant ads and/or other content to you on the Service and certain Third Party Services.

For further information on Tracking Technologies and your choices regarding them, please see “Third Party Services, Features, and Devices” and “Your Rights and Choices” below.

**C. Information Collected Automatically.**

We may obtain information about you from other sources, including Service Providers and Third Party Services, and combine such information with information we have collected about you. To the extent we combine such third party sourced information with Personal Information we have collected about you on the Service, we will treat the combined information as Personal Information under this Privacy Policy. We are not responsible for the accuracy of any information provided by third parties or third party policies or practices.

_**3\. Use of Information.**_

We may use information about you, including your Personal Information, for your legitimate interests or as permitted by applicable law, including to:

● Manage our Service;

● Facilitate the processing of your donations (we or an authorized third party on our behalf will collect and/or use your payment card and shipping information to process your donation and issue a tax receipt to you);

● Respond to your comments, questions, and requests, and provide customer service;

● Send you technical notices, updates, security alerts, information regarding changes to our policies, and support and administrative messages;

● Prevent and address fraud, breach of policies or terms, and threats or harm;

● Monitor and analyse trends, usage, and activities;

● Improve the Service or other Comic Relief websites, applications, marketing efforts, products and services;

● Send you additional information about Comic Relief;

● Solicit donations to Comic Relief;

● Send you direct marketing, including advertisements and communicate with you regarding our and third party products, services, offers, promotions, rewards and events.

We also use information about you with your consent, including to:

● Serve advertising we think you may be interested in based on your interests on our Service and Third Party Services (for information on how this works, please see “Interest-based Advertising and for more information about how to manage these communications and marketing efforts, please see “Your Rights and Choices” below); and

● Fulfill any other purpose disclosed at the time you provide Personal Information. 

_**4\. Sharing of Information.**_

Our agents, vendors, consultants, and other service providers (collectively “ **Service Providers** ”) may receive, or be given access to your information, including Personal Information and Usage Information, in connection with their work on our behalf. For example, in order to enable you to make donations and receive updates, we will share your Personal Information with (a) third parties authorized to act on our behalf, including, without limitation, credit card processing, banking and other service providers and (b) as applicable, other charitable organizations associated with your donation. If you elect to make a donation to Comic Relief through other websites, information you provide to authorized third parties on our behalf will be subject to the policies and procedures of such third parties, over which Comic Relief has no control.

These Service Providers are prohibited from using your Personal Information for any purpose other than to provide this assistance, although we may permit them to use aggregate information which does not identify you or de-identified data for other purposes.

We may also share information about you with third parties for any purposes consistent with our statements under this Privacy Policy or as permitted by applicable law, including as follows:

● To comply with the law or other legal process, and where required, in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements;

● To protect the rights, property, life, health, security and safety of us, the Service or any third party;

● In connection with, or during negotiations of, any proposed or actual merger, purchase, sale or any other type of acquisition or business combination of all or any portion of our assets, or transfer of all or a portion of our business to another business;

● With our affiliates for internal business purposes;

● With our affiliates, business partners, and other third parties for their own business purposes, including direct marketing purposes (California residents have certain rights set forth in “Your California Privacy Rights” below);

● For purposes disclosed at the time you provide Personal Information; and

● With your consent or at your direction.

Without limiting the foregoing, in our sole discretion, we may share aggregated information which does not identify you or de-identified information about you with third parties or affiliates for any purpose.

_**5\. Sweepstakes, Contests, Promotions.**_

We may offer sweepstakes, contests, surveys, and other promotions (each, a “ **Promotion** ”) jointly sponsored or offered by third parties that may require submitting Personal Information. If you voluntarily choose to enter a Promotion, your Personal Information may be disclosed to third parties for administrative purposes and as required by law (e.g., on a winners list). By entering, you agree to the official rules that govern that Promotion, and may, except where prohibited by applicable law, allow the sponsor and/or other parties to use your name, voice and/or likeness in advertising or marketing materials.

_**6\. Third Party Services, Features, and Devices.**_

Our Service contains content from and hyperlinks to websites, locations, platforms, and services operated and owned by third parties (“ **Third Party Services** ”). In addition, our Service contains features that allow you to interact with, connect to, or access our Service through certain Third Party Services and third party devices (“ **Third Party Features** ”). For example, you use a Third Party Feature when you “like” or “share” content over social media through our Service. Remember that third parties may use Tracking Technologies to independently collect information about you and may solicit Personal Information from you. Also, if you use a Third Party Feature, both we and the applicable third party may have access to and use information associated with your use of the Third Party Feature. If you publicly reference our Service on a Third Party Service (e.g., by using a hashtag associated with Comic Relief in a tweet or post), we may use your reference on or in connection with our Service.

Our Service also contains Tracking Technologies operated by third parties. For example, analytics services, such as Google Analytics, may use Tracking Technologies on our Service to help us analyze your use of the Service, compile statistic reports on the Service’s activity, and provide other services relating to Service activity and internet usage. Similarly, ad serving services, advertisers, and other third parties may use Tracking Technologies on our Service and Third Party Services to track your activities across time and services, and tailor ads to you based on your activities, which may include sending you an ad on a Third Party Service or third party device after you have left the Service ( **“Interest-based Advertising”** ).

The information collected and stored by third parties, whether through our Service, a Third Party Service, a Third Party Feature, or a third party device, remains subject to their own policies and practices, including what information they share with us, your choices on their services and devices, and whether they store information in the U.S. or elsewhere. We are not responsible for and make no representations regarding third party policies and practices, and encourage you to familiarize yourself with and consult their privacy policies and terms of use. To the extent we combine information we receive from third parties with Personal Information we collect directly from you on the Service, we will treat the combined information as Personal Information under this Privacy Policy.

For further information on Tracking Technologies and your choices regarding them, please see “Information Collected Automatically” above and “Your Rights and Choices” below.

_**7\. Your Rights and Choices.**_

**A. Accessing Your Information.**

You may access, update, or remove certain information that you have voluntarily submitted to us through the Service by sending an e-mail to us at [info@comicrelief.org](mailto:info@comicrelief.org). We may require additional information from you to allow us to confirm your identity. Please note that we will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. California residents have additional rights set forth in “Your California Privacy Rights” below.

**B. Tracking Technologies Generally.**

Regular cookies may generally be disabled or removed by tools available as part of most commercial browsers, and in some instances blocked in the future by selecting certain settings. Browsers offer different functionalities and options so you may need to set them separately. Please be aware that if you disable or remove Tracking Technologies some parts of the Service may not work and that when you revisit the Service your ability to limit browser-based Tracking Technologies is subject to your browser settings and limitations.

Your browser settings may allow you to automatically transmit a “Do Not Track” signal to online services you visit. Note, however, there is no industry consensus as to what site and app operators should do with regard to these signals. Accordingly, we do not monitor or take action with respect to “Do Not Track” signals or other mechanisms. For more information on “Do Not Track,” visit [http://www.allaboutdnt.com](http://www.allaboutdnt.com/).

**C. Analytics and Advertising Tracking Technologies.**

You may exercise choices regarding the use of cookies from Google Analytics by going to [https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout) or downloading the Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on.

You may exercise choices regarding receipt of Interest-based Advertising by submitting opt outs. Some of the advertisers and Service Providers that perform advertising-related services for us and our partners may participate in the Digital Advertising Alliance (“ **DAA** “) Self-Regulatory Program for Online Behavioral Advertising. To learn more about how you can exercise certain choices regarding Interest-based Advertising, visit [http://www.aboutads.info/choices](http://www.aboutads.info/choices), and [http://www.aboutads.info/appchoices](http://www.aboutads.info/appchoices) for information on the DAA’s opt out program for mobile apps. Some of these companies may also be members of the Network Advertising Initiative (“ **NAI** ”). To learn more about the NAI and your opt out options for their members, see [http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/). Please be aware that, even if you are able to opt out of certain kinds of Interest-based Advertising, you may continue to receive other types of ads. Opting out only means that those selected members should no longer deliver certain Interest-based Advertising to you, but does not mean you will no longer receive any targeted content and/or ads (e.g., from other ad networks). Comic Relief is not responsible for effectiveness of, or compliance with, any third-parties’ opt out options or programs or the accuracy of their statements regarding their programs.

**D. Communications.**

You can opt-out of receiving certain promotional communications (e-mails, text messages, and calls) from us at any time by (i) for e-mails, following the instructions as provided in e-mails to click on the unsubscribe link, or contacting us at [info@comicrelief.org](mailto:info@comicrelief.org) with the word UNSUBSCRIBE in the subject field of the e-mail; (ii) for text messages, texting “STOP” in response to any text message you receive from us or contacting us here and specifying you want to opt-out of text messages; and (iii) for calls, requesting opt-out during any call you receive from us or contacting us here and specifying you want to opt-out of calls. Please note that your opt-out is limited to the e-mail address, device, and phone number used and will not affect subsequent subscriptions or, for e-mails, non-promotional communications, such as those about your account, transactions, servicing, or Comic Relief’s ongoing business relations.

**E. Your California Privacy Rights.**

California’s “Shine the Light” law permits customers in California to request certain details about how certain types of their information are shared with third parties and, in some cases, affiliates, for those third parties’ and affiliates’ own direct marketing purposes. Under the law, a business should either provide California customers certain information upon request or permit California customers to opt in to, or opt out of, this type of sharing.

Comic Relief may share personal information as defined by California’s “Shine the Light” law with third parties and/or affiliates for such third parties’ and affiliates’ own direct marketing purposes. If you are a California resident and wish to obtain information about our compliance with this law, please e-mail us at [info@comicrelief.org](mailto:info@comicrelief.org) or send us a letter to Comic Relief Inc. 28 Liberty Street, 35th Floor, New York, NY 10005. Requests must include “California Privacy Rights Request” in the first line of the description and include your name, street address, city, state, and ZIP code. Please note that Comic Relief is not required to respond to requests made by means other than through the provided e-mail address or mail address.

**F. Your European Privacy Rights.**

EU data protection law makes a distinction between organizations that process personal data for their own purposes (known as “controllers”) and organizations that process personal data on behalf of other organizations (known as “processors”). Comic Relief, located at the address in the section entitled “Contact Us” below, is the controller with respect to information you provide through the Service.

If you are a data subject in Europe, you have the right to access, rectify, or erase any personal data we have collected about you through the Service. You also have the right to data portability and the right to restrict or object to our processing of personal data we have collected about you through the Service. In addition, you have the right to ask us not to process your personal data (or provide it to third parties to process) for marketing purposes or purposes materially different than for which it was originally collected or subsequently authorized by you. You may withdraw your consent at any time for any data processing we do based on consent you have provided to us.

To exercise any of these rights, contact us as set forth in the section entitled “Contact Us” below and specify which right you intend to exercise. We will respond to your request within 30 days. We may require additional information from you to allow us to confirm your identity. Please note that we store information as necessary to fulfil the purposes for which it was collected, and may continue to retain and use the information even after a data subject request for purposes of our legitimate interests, including as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, prevent fraud, and enforce our agreements.

If you have any issues with our compliance, you have the right to lodge a complaint with a European supervisory authority.

**8\. Children.**

The Service is intended for a general audience and not directed to children under sixteen (16) years of age. Comic Relief does not knowingly collect personal information as defined by the U.S. Children’s Privacy Protection Act (“ **COPPA** ”) in a manner that is not permitted by COPPA. If you are a parent or guardian and believe Comic Relief has collected such information in a manner not permitted by COPPA, please e-mail us at [info@comicrelief.org](mailto:info@comicrelief.org) or send us a letter to Comic Relief Inc. 28 Liberty Street, 35th Floor, New York, NY 10005, and we will remove such data to the extent required by COPPA.

**9\. Data Security.**

We take reasonable measures to help protect information about you from loss, theft, misuse and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration and destruction. Nevertheless, transmission via the internet is not completely secure and we cannot guarantee the security of your information collected through our Service.

**10\. International Transfer.**

We are based in the U.S. and the information we and our Service Providers collect is governed by U.S. law.  If you are accessing the Service from outside of the U.S., please be aware that information collected through the Service may be transferred to, processed, stored and used in the U.S.  Data protection laws in the U.S. may be different from those of your country of residence. Your use of the Service or provision of any information therefore constitutes your consent to the transfer to and from, processing, usage, sharing and storage of your information, including Personal Information, in the U.S. and other jurisdictions as set forth in this Privacy Policy. 

**11\. Changes to this Privacy Policy.**

Our privacy policy may change from time to time. We will post any privacy policy changes on this page and, if the changes are significant, we will provide a more prominent notice (including, for certain services, email notification of privacy policy changes). Such changes will take effect immediately once posted to the Website.

**12\. Contact Us.**

If you have questions or concerns about any of our information collection or handling practices, or if you wish to change or remove any Personal Information provided to us, please contact us by e-mail at [info@comicrelief.org](mailto:info@comicrelief.org) or by postal mail at Comic Relief, Inc. 28 Liberty Street, 35th Floor, New York, NY 10005.

### Legal Disclosure

**Comic Relief Inc. 2018  Annual Report**

You can download Comic Relief Inc’s 2018 Annual Report here.

#### Financial information

**Tax exempt status**

Comic Relief, Inc. is exempt from federal income tax under section 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code. Donations to Comic Relief, Inc. are tax deductible to the extent provided by U.S. law.

Comic Relief, Inc. retains full discretion and control over all donations received by it.

**Gift matching programs**

If your workplace matches your contributions, the following may be useful for your company giving program:

_Name:_ Comic Relief, Inc.  
 _Business address:_ Comic Relief, Inc., 28 Liberty Street, 35th Floor, New York, NY 10005  
 _Tax # (EIN):_ 01-0885377

Please email us at if you have any queries.

**Financial Information**

Comic Relief, Inc. (“CRInc”) is a Delaware non-profit non-stock corporation.

On occasion, America Gives Back (‘AGB’, now known as Comic Relief Inc and formerly known as Charity Projects Entertainment Fund) acted as a fiscal sponsor for organizations whose activities are in line with its vision and mission, including:  
Flying Start Fund  
Red Nose Day Fund

The key issues funded are health and education and the protection of children and young people at risk in the U.S. and the poorest countries in the world.

View Comic Relief Inc’s 2015 990 here.  
View Comic Relief Inc’s 2016 990 here.  
View Comic Relief Inc’s 2017 990 here.  
View Comic Relief Inc’s 2018 990 here.  
View Comic Relief Inc’s 2015/2016 Audited Financial Statement here.  
View Comic Relief Inc’s 2017 Audited Financial Statement here.  
View Comic Relief Inc’s 2018 Audited Financial Statement here.

**U.S. State Information**  
Under various state solicitation regulations, we are required to inform residents of the following U.S. states that they may also contact their state’s charities registration or licensing office for further information.

**Colorado**  – Colorado residents may obtain copies of registration and financial documents from the office of the Secretary of State, 303.894.2680, http://www.sos.state.co.us, regarding Registration Number 20073003091.

**Florida**  – FL REGISTRATION number CH 22640, a copy of the official registration and financial information may be obtained from the division of consumer services by calling toll-free, within the state 1-800-help-fla. Registration does not imply endorsement, approval, or recommendation by the state.

**Georgia – **A copy of the current financial statement of Comic Relief, Inc. is available upon request.

**Maryland – **A copy of the current financial statement of Comic Relief, Inc. is available upon request.  For the cost of copies and postage, documents and information submitted under the Maryland Solicitations Act are available from the Maryland Secretary of State, 16 Francis Street, Annapolis MD 21061 (410) 974-5521.

**Michigan**  – MICS 37060

**Minnesota – **Comic Relief, Inc. is located in New York, NY.  All contributions to Comic Relief, Inc. are tax deductible to the extent provided by US law.

**Mississippi**  – The official registration and financial information of Comic Relief, Inc. may be obtained from the Mississippi Secretary of State’s office by calling 1-888-236-6167. Registration by the Secretary of State does not imply endorsement by the Secretary of State.

**New Jersey**  – Information filed with the attorney general concerning this charitable solicitation and the percentage of contributions received by the charity during the last reporting period that were dedicated to the charitable purpose may be obtained from the attorney general of the state of New Jersey by calling 973-504-6215 and is available on the internet at http://www.njconsumeraffairs.gov/ocp.htm#charity. Registration with the attorney general does not imply endorsement.

**New York**  – Upon request, a copy of the latest annual report can be obtained from the organization or from the Office of the Attorney General by writing the Charities Bureau, 120 Broadway, New York, NY 10271.  Comic Relief, Inc. makes contributions to other organizations, and a list of all organizations that have received contributions during the past twelve months may be obtained from Comic Relief, Inc.

**North Carolina**  – Financial information about this organization and a copy of its license are available from the State Solicitation Licensing Branch at 1-888-830-4989. The license is not an endorsement by the State.

**Pennsylvania**  – The official registration and financial information of Comic Relief, Inc. may be obtained from the Pennsylvania Department of State by calling toll-free within Pennsylvania 1-800-732-0999. Registration does not imply endorsement.

**Virginia**  – Financial statements for the last fiscal year are available from the State Office of Consumer Affairs, P.O. Box 1163, Richmond, VA 23218.

**Washington   – **The registration required by the charitable solicitation act is on file with the Office of the Secretary of State. Financial and other additional information can be obtained from the Office of the Secretary of State by calling 800-332-4483 or visiting www.sos.wa.gov/charities.

**West Virginia**  – West Virginia residents may obtain a summary of the registration and financial documents from the Secretary of State, Capitol, Charleston, WV 25305. Inquiries can be made to the administrator at Comic Relief, Inc.

Last Modified: November 12, 2018
